

MILTON LENIS

SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER

/miltonIn





/MiltonLn (#) /miltonln.dev

miltonIn04@gmail.com

PROFILE

I'm a backend developer with 9+ years in the field, working in several kind of projects.

I'm a life-long learner, always ready to help and passionate about the things I do on a daily basis.

I enjoy creating things on the web and fixing complex bugs in big codebases using mostly the Python ecosystem.

PROJECTS

Virtue Poker

2022 - 2024

Poker platform.

Guided the architecture, developed new features, bug-fixing, performance improvements reducing roundtrip time

- Python 3, Django, Django Channels, WebSockets, PostgreSQL
- Datadog, Redis, Dramatiq
- ES6. ReactJS. SASS

ShipHero-API

2019 - 2022

Warehouse Management System Debugged complex problems, improved performance of gueries, escalated the database, implemented features.

- Python 3, Flask, GraphQL, MySQL, **SQLAlchemy**
- Microservices, Domain Driven Design

SKILLS

Python3 / Flask / Django

DRF / GraphQL

Django Channels / WebSockets

Redis / Celery / Datadog

Docker / AWS

MySQL / PostgreSQL

Unit Testing / Cl

Multitenancy

EDUCATION

B. S SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Universidad del Valle 2011 - 2016

- Best graduate student GPA 4.22 / 5.0
- Research Project awarded with a meritorious mention

EXPERIENCE

Monadical

Lead Developer

2022 - Present

Product development, bug-fixing, mentored other devs. talked to customers, architecture decisions

ShipHero

Senior Backend Developer

2019 - 2022

Complex bugs solving, implemented new features, escalated the product, mentored new developers.

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership

Proactivity

Team Playing

Good Communication

Results Oriented

Problem Solver